To save the world, they'll have to stick together.
The Day the Earth Blew Up: A Looney Tunes Movie is a family,
comedy, adventure film directed by Peter Browngardt.
Porky and Daffy, the classic animated odd couple, turn into unlikely heroes when their
antics at the local bubble gum factory uncover a secret alien mind control plot.
Against all odds, the two are determined to save their town (and the
world!)...that is if they don't drive each other crazy in the process.
Porky Pig / Daffy Duck (voice), played by Eric Bauza.
Petunia Pig / Old Lady (voice), played by Candi Milo.
The Invader (voice), played by Peter MacNicol.
Scientist / Farmer Jim (voice), played by Fred Tatasciore.
Mrs. Grecht (voice), played by Laraine Newman.
Mayor (voice), played by Wayne Knight.
The Day the Earth Blew Up: A Looney Tunes Movie is a 2024 American
animated science fiction comedy film produced by Warner Bros.
Directed by Pete Browngardt in his feature directorial debut, the film is a spin-off from the Looney Tunes Cartoons series developed by Browngardt,
and is the first fully animated and theatrically released film in the Looney Tunes franchise consisting of entirely original material.
It features the voices of Eric Bauza, Candi Milo, and Peter MacNicol.
The film follows Daffy Duck and Porky Pig as they try to save
Earth from a chewing gum-based alien scheme.
In 2019, while working on Looney Tunes Cartoons, Browngardt was asked if
he had any ideas for a new Looney Tunes feature film.
Browngardt eventually settled on the premise of a "sci-fi
B-movie from the '50s" starring Daffy and Porky.
He took inspiration from features of the era and
shorts starring the cartoon duo.
Warner Bros.
Animation, alongside several vendors, provided the animation for the film, of which its
character designs were modeled after the style of animator Bob Clampett.
Joshua Moshier, who previously worked on Looney Tunes
Cartoons, composed the film's score.
Upon its announcement in 2021, The Day the Earth Blew Up was originally set to be
released on HBO Max and the "ACME Night" block on Cartoon Network.
Instead, however, the film premiered at the Annecy International Animation Film Festival on June 11, 2024, and had a limited
release in the United States on December 13, 2024, by Ketchup Entertainment, before expanding wide on March 14, 2025.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and
grossed $15.3 million worldwide on a $15 million budget.
The film explores themes of chewing gum, zombie, alien
invasion, buddy comedy, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.